Burns, Eveline M. Collection of Publications 5441
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Eveline M. Burns Collection of Publications
1880-1958
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Burns, Eveline M. (Eveline Mabel), 1900-1985
5441
6 cubic feet
6 linear ft.
Publications.
Books on German, British, and Latin American labor and Social Security donated by Dr. Eveline M. Burns, emeritus professor of Columbia School of Social Work.
5649079
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, November 01, 2007
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, April 19, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5249: Henry R. Seager research notes and monographs 5336: Independent Labour Party (Great Britain) Pamphlets 5337: Labour Party (Great Britain) Pamphlets 5338: Trades Union Congress (Great Britain) Pamphlets
Labor -- Great Britain; Labor -- Germany; Social security -- Great Britain; Social security -- Germany; Burns, Eveline Mabel Richardson, 1900-
5649079
- TUC (Trades Union Congress), 1928-1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: No Pauperisation of the Unemployed: The Fight Against the U.A.B. Regulations, 1935; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Author: J. L. Smyth
    Language: English.
  - Item 2: Unemployment Assistance: Means Test Regulations, 1935; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: Industrial Conference Report, 1928; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: TUC (Trades Union Congress)
  - Item 4: The Trade Unions and Workmen's Compensation: The Case for Reform, 1939; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Walter Citrine
  - Item 5: No United Front With Communism, 1936; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Walter Citrine; R. G. Crane; E. J. Evans; B. H. Coley; E. Howley; B. Quinn: John Stokes; A. Falconer
    Notes: Report of Speeches at the Plymouht Trade Union Congress
  - Item 6: Trade Unions and the War Situation, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Trade Unionism in Central Europe: T.U.C. Survey, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 8: The T.U.C. In War-Time, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 9: The T.U.C. In War-Time, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 10: The T.U.C. In War-Time, 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 11: What the T.U.C. Is Doing, 1937; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 12: What the T.U.C. Is Doing, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
- The Labour Party Annual Reports, 1906-1909 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Report of the Sixth Annual Conference of the Labour Party, 1906; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: The Labour Party
    Notes: February 15-17, 1906. Memorial Hall, London.
  - Item 2: Report of the Seventh Annual Conference of the Labour Party, 1907; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Notes: January 24-26, 1907. The Wellington Hall, Belfast.
  - Item 3: Report of the Eighth Annual Conference of the Labour Party, 1908; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Notes: January 20-22, 1908. The Assembly Hall, Hull.
  - Item 4: Report of the Nineth Annual Conference of the Labour Party, 1909; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Notes: January 27-29, 1909. The Town Hall, Portsmouth.
- The Labour Party Annual Reports, 1910-1931 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Report of the Tenth Annual Conference of the Labour Party, 1910; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: Report of the Eventh Annual Conference of the Labour Party, 1911; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: February 1-3, 1911. The Temperance Hall, Leicester.
  - Item 3: Report of the National Executive Committee to the Thirty-First Annual Conference, 1931; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: October 5-9, 1931. The Grand Hall, The Spa, Scarborough
- Labour, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Labour, 1941; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Notes: v.3:no.11 (1941:July). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 2: Labour, 1941; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Notes: v.3:no.12 (1941:Aug.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 3: Labour, 1941; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Notes: v.4:no.1 (1941:Sep.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 4: Labour, 1942; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Notes: v.4:no.7 (1942:Mar.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 5: Labour, 1942; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Notes: v.4:no.8 (1942:Apr.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 6: Labour, 1942; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Notes: v.4:no.10 (1942:June). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 7: Labour, 1942; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Notes: v.5:no.5 (1942:Dec.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 8: Labour, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Notes: v.5:no.5 (1943:Jan.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 9: Labour, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Notes: v.5:no.6 (1943:Feb.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 10: Labour, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Notes: v.5:no.7 (1947:mar.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 11: Labour, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Notes: v.5:no.8 (1943:Apr.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 12: Labour, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Notes: v.5:no.11 (1943:July). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 13: Labour, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Notes: v.5:no.12 (1943:Aug.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
- Labour, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Labour, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: v.6:no.2 (1943:Oct.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 2: Labour, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: v.6:no.4 (1943:Dec.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 3: Labour, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: v.6:no.5 (1944:Jan.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 4: Labour, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: v.6:no.10 (1944:June). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 5: Labour, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: v.6:no.12 (1944:Aug.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 6: Labour, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: v.7:no.2 (1944:Oct.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 7: Labour, 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: v.7:no.6 (1945:Feb.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 8: Labour, 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: v.7:no.7 (1945:Mar.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 9: Labour, 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: v.7:no.9 (1945:May). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 10: Labour, 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: v.7:no.10 (1945:June). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 11: Labour, 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: v.7:no.11 (1945:July). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 12: Labour, 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: v.7:no.12 (1945:Aug.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
- Labour, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Labour, 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: v.8:no.1 (1945:Sep.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 2: Labour, 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: v.8:no.3 (1945:Nov.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 3: Labour, 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: v.8:no.4 (1945:Dec.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 4: Labour, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: v.8:no.5 (1946:Jan.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 5: Labour, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: v.8:no.6 (1946:Feb.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 6: Labour, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: v.8:no.8 (1948:Apr.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 7: Labour, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: v.8:no.9 (1946:May). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 8: Labour, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: v.8:no.10 (1946:June). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 9: Labour, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: v.8:no.11 (1946:July). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
  - Item 10: Labour, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: v.9:no.2 (1946:Oct.). Official organ of the Trades Union Congress.
- League for Industrial Democracy, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: A Program for Labor and Progressives, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Author: Harry W. Laidler
  - Item 2: Harry W. Laidler, 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Author: Current Biography
    Notes: Reprint from Current Biography 1945
  - Item 3: The Atomic Age: Suicide, Slavery or Social Planning?, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Author: Aaron Levenstein
  - Item 4: British Labor on Reconstruction in War and Peace, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Notes: L.I.D. Pamphlet Series: The Old World and the New Society
  - Item 5: Thirtieth Anniversary Report, 1905-1935, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Author: Norman Thomas; Harry W. Laidler
- Central Joint Advisory Committee on Tutorial Classes., 1914-1922 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Fourth Annual Report of the Committee for the Session 1912-1913, 1914; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Author: Central Joint Advisory Committee on Tutorial Classes
  - Item 2: Fourth Annual Report of the Committee for the Session 1913-1914, 1915; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 3: Fourth Annual Report of the Committee for the Session 1914-1915, 1916; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 4: Fourth Annual Report of the Committee for the Session 1915-1916, 1917; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 5: Fourth Annual Report of the Committee for the Session 1916-1917, 1918; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 6: Fourth Annual Report of the Committee for the Session 1917-1919, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 7: Fourth Annual Report of the Committee for the Session 1919-1920, 1921; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 8: Fourth Annual Report of the Committee for the Session 1920-1921, 1922; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Central Joint Advisory Committee on Tutorial Classes., 1923-1928 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Fourth Annual Report of the Committee for the Session 1921-1922, 1923; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 2: Fourth Annual Report of the Committee for the Session 1922-1923, 1924; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 3: Fourth Annual Report of the Committee for the Session 1923-1924, 1925; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 4: Fourth Annual Report of the Committee for the Session 1924-1925, 1926; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 5: Fourth Annual Report of the Committee for the Session 1925-1926, 1927; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 6: Fourth Annual Report of the Committee for the Session 1926-1928, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Women and Labour, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Sex Differentiation in Salary, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: H. F. Normanton
  - Item 2: Opportunies for Women in the Workers' Education Association, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: Workers' Education Association
  - Item 3: Workers' Educatinal Association Educational Facilities for Women, 1926; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: Annie Somers; Eleanor Calthrop; Grace M. Colman
    Notes: Report of a Women's Education Committee
  - Item 4: Labour Laws for Women in Australia and New Zealand, 1906; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: Womens Industrial Council
  - Item 5: Labour Laws for Women in France, 1907; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 6: Women's Wages in England in the Nineteenth Century, 1906; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 7: Labour Laws for Women in Germany, 1907; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Unemployment, 1930-1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Unemployment Assistance Guide, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Author: G. Grant McKenzie
  - Item 2: Notes on Unemployment Assistance Regulations, 1936, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 3: Report of the Interstate Commission on Unemployment Insurance, 1932; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Author: Leo Wolman; Charles R. Blunt; A. Lincoln Filene; C. A. Kulp; W. M. Leiserson; W. J. Couper
    Notes: March, 1932.
  - Item 4: Unemployment and the Cost of Living, 1937; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 5: What's Wrong With Unemployment Insurance, 1930; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Author: Ronald C. Davison
  - Item 6: Unemployment Insurance: An Analysis of the Present Position, 1930; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Labour Party Speaker's Handbooks, 1929-1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: The Labour Speech and How To Make It, 1932; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Author: Fred Montague
  - Item 2: Local Government Speaker's Handbook, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 3: Local Government Speaker's Handbook, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 4: Labour Speaker's Handbook, 1929; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 5: Labour Speaker's Handbook: Facts and Figures for the Workers, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bureau of Labor Statistics. Monthly Labor Review Indexes, 1924-1929 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 19, 1925; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: Bureau of Labor Statistics
    Notes: July-December, 1924.
  - Item 2: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 20, 1925; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Notes: January-June, 1925.
  - Item 3: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 21, 1926; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Notes: July-December, 1925.
  - Item 4: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 23, 1927; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Notes: July-December, 1926.
  - Item 5: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 24, 1927; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Notes: January-June, 1927.
  - Item 6: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 25, 1928; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Notes: July-December, 1927.
  - Item 7: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 27, 1929; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Notes: July-December, 1928.
  - Item 8: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 18, 1924; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Notes: January-June, 1924.
- Bureau of Labor Statistics. Monthly Labor Review Indexes, 1930-1938 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 30, 1930; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Notes: January-June, 1930.
  - Item 2: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 31, 1931; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Notes: July-December, 1930.
  - Item 3: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 35, 1933; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Notes: July-December, 1932.
  - Item 4: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 36, 1933; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Notes: January-June, 1933.
  - Item 5: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 38, 1935; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Notes: January-June, 1934.
  - Item 6: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 39, 1935; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Notes: July-December, 1934.
  - Item 7: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 40, 1935; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Notes: January-June, 1935.
  - Item 8: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 41, 1936; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Notes: July-December, 1935.
  - Item 9: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 42, 1937; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Notes: January-June, 1936.
  - Item 10: Monthly Labor Review: Index to Volume 44, 1938; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Notes: January-June, 1937.
- Labour Party, 1937; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Labour and the Distressed Areas: A Programme of Immediate Action, 1937; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Author: Hugh Dalton; George Dallas; Barbara Ayrton Gould
    Notes: Interim Report of the Labour Party's Commission of Enquiry into the Distressed Areas
  - Item 2: West Cumberland, 1937; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Author: Hugh Dalton; George Dallas; Barbara Ayrton Gould; G. Grant McKenzie
    Notes: Report of the Labour Party's Commission of Enquiry into the Distressed Areas
- The Co-Operative Union, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Report of the Central Education Committee of the Co-Operative Union for the Congress Year 1927-1928, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Author: W. R. Rae; F. Hall; C. E. Wood
    Notes: As prepared for submission to the Hartlepoole Co-Operative Congress
  - Item 2: Educational Programme: Session 1927-1928, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Author: The Co-Operative Union
- Independent Labour Party, 1932; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Preliminary Agenda of Resolutions to be Submitted to the 40th Annual Conference, 1932; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Independent Labour Party
    Notes: March 26-29, 1932. Blackpool
  - Item 2: Resolutions to be Submitted to the 40th Annual Conference, 1932; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Notes: March 26-29, 1932. Final Agenda. Blackpool
  - Item 3: First Agenda for the Special National Conference, 1932; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Notes: July 30-31, 1932. Jowett Hall, Bradford
  - Item 4: Resolutions to be Submitted to the Special National Conference, 1932; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Notes: July 30-31, 1932. Final Agenda. Jowett Hall, Bradford
- Fabian Society. Francis Place, 1919; Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: Francis Place: The Tailor of Charing Cross, 1919; Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Author: St. John G. Ervine
    Notes: Fabian Tract no.165. Biographical Series no.1. First published 1912.
- Reprints from American Economic Review and Other Journals, 1925-1942 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: American Labor Relations Act, 1937; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Author: Paul H. Douglas
    Notes: Reprint from American Economic Review, v.27:no.4 (1937:Dec.).
  - Item 2: The Effect of the War on the Position of Labor, 1942; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Author: Carter Goodrich
    Notes: Reprint from American Economic Review Supplement, v.32:no.1 (1942:Mar.).
  - Item 3: Competitive Exchange as a Method of Interesting Workmen in Output and Cost, 1925; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Author: Sumner H. Slichter
    Notes: Reprint from American Economic Review Supplement, v.15:no.1 (1925:Mar.).
  - Item 4: The Worker in Modern Economic Society, 1926; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Notes: Reprint from Journal of Political Economy, v.34:no.1 (1926:Feb.)
  - Item 5: The Fair Wage Principle in New Zealand, 1937; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Author: E. J. Riches
    Notes: Reprint from Economic Record, December, 1937.
- Self and Society Booklets, 1928; Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: The Faith of a Democrat, 1928; Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Author: Philip Snowden
    Notes: Self and Society Booklets, no.1
  - Item 2: Labour and the Community, 1928; Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Author: Walter M. Citrine
    Notes: Self and Society Booklets, no.7
- Amalgamated Society of Carpenters and Joiners, 1880; Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: The Twentieth Annual Report of the Amalgamated Society of Carpenters and Joiners, 1880; Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Author: Amalgamated Society of Carpenters and Joiners
    Notes: December 1978 through December 1979
- Industrial Disease Commission, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Item 1: Report to the General Court of the Special Industrial Disease Commission, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Author: Edwin S. Smith; Merton P. Brown; Henry D. Chadwick; Joseph A. Parks; Joseph E. Warner
    Notes: February, 1934.
- U.S. Congress., 1935-1938 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Item 1: An Act to Provide for the Establishment of Fair Labor Standards in Employments In and Affecting Interstate Commerce, and for Other Purposes, 1938; Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Author: U.S. Congress
    Notes: Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938
  - Item 2: Report, 1935; Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Author: NLRB (National Labor Relations Board)
    Notes: House of Representatives Report no.972
- Postwar Labor, 1919-1943 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Item 1: Memorandum on the Industrial Situation After the War, 1919; Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Author: The Garton Foundation
  - Item 2: International Postwar Problems, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Author: William Green; Clinton S. Golden; Robert M. MacIver; Alvin H. Hanson; Albert Halasi, Arthur J. Altmeyer; Afred Braunthal
    Notes: v.1:no.1 (1943:Dec.)
- Miners, Publication (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Item 1: Constitution, Publication (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Author: British Mineworkers' Union
  - Item 2: Further Facts from the Coal Commission, Publication (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Author: R. Page Arnot; Robert Smillie; Frank Hodges
- British Labour History, 1920-1926 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Item 1: A History of Trades Union Councils, 1860-1875, 1920; Publication (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Author: Cicely Richards; G. D. H. Cole
  - Item 2: A Short History of the British Workers, 1926; Publication (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Author: Raymond W. Postgate; J. F. Horrabin
- The Labour Abstainer, 1933; Publication (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Item 1: The Labour Abstainer, 1933; Publication (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Author: The Workers' Temperance League
    Notes: no.4 (1933:Fourth Quarter)
- US Labor, 1923-1943 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Item 1: The Supreme Court and the Minimum Wage, 1923; Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Author: John A. Ryan
    Notes: The Missionary Society of St. Paul the Apostle in the State of New York
  - Item 2: Workers' Education Today, 1941; Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Author: Mark Starr
    Notes: L.I.D. Pamphlet Series
  - Item 3: Child Labor Facts, 1939-1940, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Author: Gertrude Folks Zimand
    Notes: October, 1939. Publication no.379
  - Item 4: Labor Under the NRA, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Author: Carroll R. Daugherty
  - Item 5: Farm Labour Research in the United States, 1932; Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Author: Josiah C. Folsom
    Notes: Reprinted from the International Labour Review, v.25:no.5 (1932:May).
  - Item 6: Labor Cases and Materials: Readings on the Relations between Government and Labor, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Author: Carl Raushenbush; Emanuel Stein
    Notes: Pre-publication table of contents.
  - Item 7: Wages and the Movement of Factory Labor, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Author: W. Rupert MacLaurin; Charles A. Myers
    Notes: Reprinted from the Quarterly Journal of Economics, February, 1943. Series 2:no.10
- British Government and Labour, 1923-1946 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Item 1: The Question of the House of Lords, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Author: A. L. Rowse
    Notes: Day to Day Pamphlets, no.19.
  - Item 2: Government Publications Issued during April 1946, Publication (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Author: His Majesty's Stationery Office
  - Item 3: Labour and Capital in Parliament, 1923; Publication (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Author: Labour Research Department
    Notes: Studies in Labour and Capital, v.3.
- Mond's Manacles, 1928; Publication (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Item 1: Mond's Manacles: The Destruction of Trade Unionism, 1928; Publication (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Author: A. J. Cook; Arthur Horner
    Notes: Being a sequel to "Mond Moonshine"